# **Mohammad Abubakar Mamoon**

<u>Cellular Phone</u>: +92 332 3715731 | <u>E-mail ID</u>: abubakrmianmamoon@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn Profile</u>: https://pk.linkedin.com/in/abubakar-mamoon-439a3bb7

#### Summary

Working at RIGHT SOLUTIONS since February 2016 on PHP laravel as BACKEND LEAD. I have also worked for five (5) years as freelancer in various programming languages across different platforms.

#### About Me

I am passionate developer keen to lean new technologies I have strong OOP, database and problem solving skills, I started my career as free lance C# developer after first year at my university then I started working as android developer, I worked on C sharp and android for three years during my university, then I learned php laravel and start working at right solutions as junior php developer but with hard work and learning capabilities I soon got the position of **BACKEND** LEAD, I am currently learning react native. Looking forward to work in renowned company where I can polish my skills, I will prove myself to be a valuable asset for your company InshAllah.

#### **Professional Skills**

Web Application Development			Database Management
	Server Side Script	Client Side Script	System
•	PHP (core, Laravel 5x) Dot net C#(MVC) C# Windows Store App	<ul><li>jQuery</li><li>Android</li><li>React Native</li></ul>	• SQL • NoSQL

#### **Employment History**

- Software Engineer at Right Solution, Karachi, Pakistan (Feb 2016 to present)
- Software Engineer at Dev Enhanced, Karachi, Pakistan (Dec 2014 to Feb 2015)
- Freelance (Jun 2012 to 2017)

### **Detailed Experience**

# <u>Team Lead Right Solution, Karachi, Pakistan</u> (November 2017 to present)



#### Responsibilities

- · Application architecture design.
- Distributing Responsibilities to take care of web services, web application and mobile applications.
- Maintaining the application flow.
- Resolving issues.

# Projects: Transporter App, E-commerce App, Online Services Booking

- Backend server for web service (REST api)
- Web application admin panel
- Database Designs
- Request and Response Designs in Apairy.

#### **Project Name: Transporter online Role: Team Lead**

• Online cargo service booking where drivers and users both can create their journeys, multiple users can join journey created by driver.

#### Project Name: E-commerce App online Role: Team Lead

Vendors can create their products and add multiple suppliers to deliver their products with their drivers each supplier can have multiple google map polygon regions where their products are available , when a user login to his app his location is checked with the available suppliers in that particular region, users are then shown vendors for that particular region suppliers, when user buy some products a notification is sent to supplier if he confirms his order this delivery is assigned to driver of that particular region.

#### Project Name: Book appointment with clinics-Role: Team Lead

 User can search for clinics of specific category, he can then select particular doctor and book his particular slot.

<u>Senior Software Engineer at Right Solution, Karachi, Pakistan</u> (February 2016 to November 2017)

#### Responsibilities



- Responsibility to take care of web services and web application php (Laravel5.x)
- Writing API requests and responses

#### Project: Book online Trainer App, Car maintenance, share ride, ecommerce: Software Engineer

- Backend server for web service (REST api)
- Web application admin panel
- Database Designs
- · Request and Response Designs in Apairy.

#### Project Name: Book online trainer- CRM Project's booking online Role: Development Engineer

- Online gym trainer booking where people can book their trainers, chat with them and follow their pushed regime from trainer or created by them.
- Admin web application where super admin can add trainers, delete reviews and reporting by table and bar graph (Based on Laravel 5 frame work).

#### Project Name: - A Car Maintenance Project Role: Software Analyst/Development

- A car maintenance app reminds your car services dates and help you find nice garage nearby.
- Admin web application where super admin can register new garages services and check overall reporting by tables and graphs (Based on Laravel 5 frame work).

#### Project Name: - Communication app Role: Software Development Engineer

• Help people communicate travelling to same destination so they can share rides promotions 

Reporting registered users and booked rides (Based on Laravel 5 frame work).

# Project Name: – CRM People can buy flowers and chocolates Role: Software Analyst/Development Engineer

- Maintenance of Dashboard where inventories and promotions.
- Admin web application add new vendors, delete reviews add products and see reports (Based on Laravel 5 frame work).

# Project Name: - CRM People advertise their small business Role: Analyst/Software Development Engineer

 Maintenance of Dashboard where inventories and promotions (Based on Laravel 5 frame work)

- Admin can add products with as many parameters as he want, make promotions for his city and out of city delivered products.
- See his products sale reports date wise, table and graph reports.
- Super admin can add admin delete their reviews graph of vendors rating add new vendors sales reporting by tables and graphs (Based on Laravel 5 frame work).

# Project Name: – An E-commerce Application Role: Analyst/Software Development Engineer

- People can compare products rates of different vendors.
- Admin web application can add new vendors, delete review and see reports in table and bar graphs.

# Project Name: - An Advertisement Application Role: Software Development Engineer

 $\square$  People can find and write reviews for nearby businesses like restaurants, malls etc.  $\square$  Admin web application can add new businesses delete reviews and see reporting by tables and graphs .

### Freelance (June 2012 to 2017)

### Analyst/Development ·

Android Application.

- C# desktop application
- C# windows store application
- · C# Model View Controller

Project	Short Description	Website URL
EmkayLine	Android Application	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=co.Qsoft.Emkayline
OldRavians	Developed Websites: (MVC- ASP.Net)	• www.orchskarachi.com
Bakery Invoice	Windows Form Application. C#	■ Deployed at Pak Yeast

Developed School Management System	Windows Form Application. C#	■ To be deployed at iota world
Kids	Windows Store Application. C#	■ To be deployed at MAK

#### **Education**

• Bachelor of Science in Computer Science from Iqra University, Karachi, in 2015

#### **Achievements & Awards**

- Secured 1<sup>st</sup> Position in SPARK 2014 Speed Programming held at Mohammad Ali Jinnah University.
- Runner up in SPARK 2014 Design Algorithm held at Mohammad Ali Jinnah University.

# **Participation**

• 6th position Procom Speed Programming competition held at Fast-PROCOM, Karachi (Apr, 2014)

#### **Personal Information**

Cellular Phone: primary: +92 332 3715731, secondary: +923362826068

Father's Name: Mian Mamoon Ashraf

Place of Birth: Lahore

Date of Birth: 3<sup>rd</sup> November 1990

Language: Urdu, English

Marital Status: Single